在左边，我们有一堆要组装的零件，
Over here on the left, we have a bunch of pieces that we're going to assemble,
我们向用户展示的小乐高积木。
little Legos that we're exposing to the user.
在右边，我们有一个紫色的盒子。
On the right, we have a purple box.
所以这是一种试图捕捉一点点的想法，一堆小
And so this is kind of trying to capture the idea of a little, bunch of little
您编写的函数与完成所有工作的一个大函数。
functions that you compose versus one big function that does all the work.
我们正在编写的小函数的好处之一
And one of the benefits here of the little functions that we're composing
我们是否得到了无限的用例，比如
is we get infinite use cases like the combinatorics of
您可以组合函数以创建新功能的所有方式。
all the ways you can compose the functions to create new functionality.
我们只是将这些提供给用户并说，你知道的，说去吧，发疯。
We're just giving those to the user and say, you know, saying go, go nuts.
享受这些功能的乐趣并制作您自己的应用程序。
Have fun with these these functions and make your own apps.
我们最终得到一些简单易懂的片段，
We end up with little simple, understandable pieces,
通常高度可重用，这里有很多很多优点。
often highly reusable, lots of, lots of goodness here.
但也很难改变实现。
But it's also hard to change the implementation.
这更难。
It's harder.
如果我们要试试这个
And if we're gonna try this,
当我们将所有部分提供给用户时，我们获得灵活性的方式
the way we get flexibility when we give all the pieces to our users
撰写是通过强制执行这些作品中的每一个以有原则的方式撰写。
to compose is by enforcing that each of these pieces compose in a principled way.
我们可以随心所欲地更改实现，只要它们仍然有效
And we can change the implementation all we want as long as they still hold
我们正在定义的合约。
the contracts that we're defining.
所以这主要是代数，抽象代数的工作原理是你有这些部分
So this is largely how algebra, abstract algebra works is you have these pieces
你可以用很多不同的方式摆姿势，但这些作品有构图法则，
that you can pose in many different ways, but those pieces have laws of composition,
您可以通过多种不同的方式实现它们。
and you can implement them in many different ways.
因此，这为您提供了很大的灵活性，但您必须真正做到这一点。
So that gives you a lot of flexibility but you have to really work at that.
而且用户作曲也更难了，对吧？
And it's also harder for the user to compose, right?
他们必须像，一直把所有这些碎片放在一起。
They have to go like, put all these pieces together all the time.
进入事物的另一面，我们有一个盒子的极端另一面，
Getting into the other side of things, the extreme other side where we have a box,
你给我输入，我给你输出，它为你做一切。
you give me input, I'll give you output, and it does everything for you.
虽然我们有很多灵活性和实施变更，但我们可以
While we have a lot of flexibility and implementation changes we can
取一个值并做我们想做的任何事情，只要它返回相同的输出。
take a value and do whatever we want as long as it returns the same output.
我们可以改变这一整天。
We can we can change this all day long.
但是支持和支持的用例较少
But there's less use cases out there to support and
他们只能用这个功能做一件事。
they only can kind of do one thing with this function.
但是如果我们用名字和合同来捕获这个过程，并且
But if we're capturing this procedure with a name and contract, and
我们在世界上代表与其他人组成
we're representing out in the world to be composed with other
每个其他程序的一部分。
parts of every other program.
从本质上讲，您将不可避免地遇到以下情况：
Essentially, you're gonna inevitably run into a case where you
传入 if else 或某种标志，或者如果你想重用这个单元
pass in an if else or some kind of flag, or something if you wanna reuse this unit
以不同的方式，所以这些条件被推入
in different ways, so those conditionals get pushed into
当我们以不同的方式创作时，而不是在外面。
the box rather than being out when we compose in different ways.
那有意义吗？
Does that make sense?
我现在说的很抽象。
I'm talking pretty abstract right now.
[笑] 但我们的想法是，如果我们编写一个巨大的函数，
[LAUGH] But the idea is that if we write one giant function,
并且我们需要在不同的地方使用它，如果 else 在函数内，则不可避免。
and we need to use it in different places, inevitably if else is within the function.
我们不能用很少的 if else 来满足所有的情况，对吧？
We can't satisfy all the cases with few if else's, right?
与提供一堆用于编写的功能相比，这是最小的。
The is minimal compared to providing a bunch of functions for composing.
你得到的方式更少，所以有时这是正确的决定。
You get way less so sometimes this is the right decision.
有时这是正确的决定。
And sometimes this is the right decision.
但我们今天将专注于这个决定。
But we're going to focus on this decision today.
那是因为，
And that's because,
大多数情况下，这将在您的应用程序开发中获得回报。
most of the time this will pay off in your application development.
当你在这儿的时候，这里的这个会得到更多的回报
This one over here will pay off much more when you're
开发一个只做一件事的库。
developing a library that does one thing.
所以就像抽象代数的一个简单例子，这是
So just as a quick example of the abstract algebra stuff, this is
group 的定义来自维基百科，我们可以定义这么多组。
the definition of group from Wikipedia, and we can define so many groups.
如果你看像组的实例，它们就像到处都是
If you look at like instances of groups, they're just like everywhere and they're
只要满足这些特性，就可以自由地以不同的方式实现。
free to implement in different ways, as long as they satisfy these properties.
这就是您的文档的样子。
This is what your documentation can look like.
相反，你知道，它被称为 this 并把它放到那个输出和
Versus, you know, it's called this and take this and put to that output and
你对如何创作它一无所知。
you don't know anything else about how you can compose it.
所以最后一个注意事项是有时你构建一个应用程序，它是这样的
So one last note on that is sometimes you build an app and its like this and
它的美妙。
its wonderful.
就像，你知道，这是我的图书馆，这是我的应用程序。
Like, this is, you know, my library, this is my application.
我们有所有这些小功能，您可以编写它们，这很棒。
We have all these little functions and you compose them, it's great.
有时就是这样。
And sometimes it's like this.
和组合并没有真正买多少。
And composition doesn't really buy much.
你真的会有一个像其中一个很棒的，叫做汽车巡洋舰战斗机？
You really gonna have an awesome like one of those, called car cruiser fighters?
不，我会在互联网上遇到很多麻烦。
No, I'm going to be in so much trouble with the internet.
&gt;&gt; X 翼 &gt;&gt; X 翼。
&gt;&gt; X wing &gt;&gt; X wing.
我猜它是一个 X。
I guess it makes an X.
是的，好吧，无论如何星球大战传单的事情，
Yeah, well, anyway Star Wars battle flyer thing,
你会拥有一个，或者你不会拥有它，对吧？
you're gonna have one or you're not gonna have it, right?
对于用户来说，每次都必须重新组合这个东西并不是很有用
It's not going to be very useful for the user to have to recompose this thing every
除非这对孩子们来说是一个有趣的游戏。
time unless it's a fun game for the children.
所以我们主要倾向于可组合的函数。
So we're gonna favor composable functions, mostly.
我只是想提醒一下，如果你是，如果你一直都知道，
I just wanted to call out that caveat like if you're if you're always you know,
遵守这些原则，您可能会做出错误的决定。
abiding by these these principles, you might make the wrong decision.
有时，在大多数情况下，它只是进入正确解决方案的良好指路明灯。
Sometimes it's just a good guiding light into the right solution most of the time.